Professional Summary

Highly analytical and astute finance professional with 6 years of work experience in the field of Finance and Tax. Formulated process driven work environment and cost saving solution through financial forecast and market research. Experienced in managing financial operations such as planning, forecasting and budgeting as well as accounting operations such as accounts receivable/payable and BRS. Result oriented finance specialist with leadership and decision making skills to achieve business aligned goals.

Experience

A R Alloys | Finance Manager | Coimbatore, Tamilnadu, India

2019 - Present

- Setting up of business process through financial planning related to procurement of high demand goods as and when they are below the threshold limit.
- Developed new suppliers and made decision between cash/credit purchases based on financial situation, resulting in 5% increase in profit margins.
- Streamlined the inventory management system by changing it from manual to ERP based, to keep 100% track as well as increase work efficiency.
- Maintained accurate records to keep track of Accounts Receivables (AR) and follow up with the customers. Also prepared BRS making sure enough cash balance will be available for the upcoming dues to Accounts Payable (AP).
- Derived methods to set off Input GST to Output GST in a way that reduces the payables and mitigates unattended GST carryforwards from prior years.
- Decided to switch from a normal bank cc account to GST based loan account resulting in 2% reduction in interest rate thereby saving Rs.15000 each month.
- Administered accurate reporting of financial statement and provided assistance to the company auditors during year-end audit and filing of Income Tax returns.

Grant Thornton LLP | Tax Associate | Bangalore, Karnataka, India 2017 – 2019

- Delivered multiple high priority US Tax returns under a tight deadline
- Recognized as a key preparer on a large scale trust returns with overall budget of 200 hours which includes communication and data gathering from US team
- Achieved annual goal of 2800 hours, one of the highest clocked hours among the peers by working in multiple mid and high range projects throughout the year.
- Conducted presentation on new projects in the midst of seniors and managers
- Managing and briefing the new team for their on-boarding and training in US
 Tax Returns and supporting the team in their initial client returns.
- Selected to be a part of long term project where 1040 returns were to be signed within India after video call meeting with US Team preparers and managers.

Education

2015 – 2017 MBA Finance | KCT Business School | Coimbatore, Tamilnadu

2010 - 2013 Bachelor of Commerce | Madura College | Madurai, Tamilnadu

Internship - CA Articleship

V Ramaswamy Iyer & Co. | CA Intern | Dindigul, Tamilnadu, India

2013 - 2015 • Auditing of books of accounts of various clients

• Preparation of Tax returns for individuals and corporates

Tools

Tally Prime

MS Excel (Vlookup, Table, Pivot and Graph)

MS Powerpoint

Google Sheets

Excel Macros

Chat - GPT

QuickBooks

GST

Skills

Budgeting & Forecasting

Financial Reporting

Data Analysis

Strategic Planning

Leadership

Certificates

Best Performer in PWS C2C training

NSDC led Global
Investment Banking

Best sales and overall award for leading a five member team

Creating Budget with Microsoft Excel

IIBA led Foundation of the Business Analysis

Languages

English - Fluent

Hindi - Native

Tamil - Conversational